噢 伟大无敌的拉普
Oh, great and mighty Rapu…
我们向您祈求水与粮食
we pray to you for water and sustenance.
不是为我自己 而是为了我女儿
I pray to you, not for me, but for my daughter.
我好累
I'm tired.
你受尽苦难
You have suffered.
过来
Come to me.
你受尽苦难
You have suffered.
过来
Come to me.
你受尽苦难
You have suffered.
这是什么东西？
What do we have here?
你看看
Look at it.
它狼吞虎咽我的水果
It's gobbling up all my fruit.
拉普
Rapu.
光明使者
Bringer of Light.
是我的信徒
Oh, it's one of mine.
我是格尔 您最后的门徒
I am Gorr, the last of your disciples.
我们失去了所有 我的主
We have lost everything, my lord.
土地干涸
The land is dry.
生灵涂炭
All life is lost.
但对您的信仰未曾动摇 如今就等待
But our faith in you never wavered and now we await the promise…
您永恒的恩典
of the eternal reward.
所以您才在庆祝吗？
Is this why you celebrate?
他以为有永恒的恩典
He thinks there's an eternal reward.
不 不好意思
No. No, sorry.
没有永恒的恩典给你 狗东西
There's no eternal reward for you, dog!
我们在庆祝刚杀了人
What we're celebrating is a fresh kill.
铲除了死灵剑的持有者
We just vanquished the holder of the Necrosword…
- 你受尽苦难　- 免得他…
- You have suffered. - before he could harm…
- 用那把诅咒之剑杀神　- 如果想复仇
- any other gods with that cursed blade. - If it's revenge you seek.
他威胁要终结我的帝国
He threatened to end my entire empire.
可是我的主…
But, my lord…
您的帝国已经终结了
your empire has already ended.
没有人崇拜您了
There's no one left to worship you.
有更多追随者会取代你
There'll be more followers to replace you.
源源不绝
There always are.
我们受苦
We have suffered…
我们挨饿
and we have starved.
我女儿死了
My daughter died…
- 以您之名　- 应该的
- in your name. - And well you should.
为你的神受苦是你唯一的使命
Suffering for your gods is your only purpose.
死后没东西给你了
There's nothing for you after death.
除了死亡
Except death.
你不是神
You are no god.
我决定弃绝你
I renounce you.
现在你无意义的生命终于有了价值
Now your meaningless life finally does have a purpose.
为我牺牲你自己
To sacrifice yourself to me.
如果你想复仇
If it's revenge you seek…
屠杀众神
…kill all the gods.
前往永恒
Go to Eternity.
如果你想复仇
If it's revenge you seek…
召唤彩虹桥
summon the Bifrost.
前往永恒
Go to Eternity.
- 屠杀众神　- 召唤彩虹桥
- Kill all the gods. - Summon the Bifrost.
前往永恒
Go to Eternity.
屠杀众神…
Kill all the gods. Kill all the gods. Kill all the gods.
这把剑选择了你
The sword chose you.
现在你受到了诅咒
You are now cursed!
奇怪
Funny.
感觉不像诅咒
It doesn't feel like a curse.
感觉像承诺
Feels like a promise.
这是我的誓约
So, this is my vow.
众神将亡
All gods will die.
过来 围过来
Come, come, gather round.
过来听太空维京人的传奇
And listen to the legend of the Space Viking.
也就是雷霆之神 又名索尔奥汀森
AKA the God of Thunder. AKA Thor Odinson.
从小被当成战士培养
Raised in the way of the warrior…
索尔学习协助打赢战争
Thor was taught to help win battles…
为无力反抗的人打赢正义之战
fighting the good fight for those who can't fight good.
他一天一天成长茁壮
He grew and he grew and he grew.
体贴敏感 宛如一抹微笑
He was sensitive, like a smile.
他的爱心不分贵贱
And his loving nature did not discriminate.
他爱过爱到卡惨死的激情女郎
He once loved a swashbuckling Passionista.
还有一次爱上女狼人
Another time, he loved a Wolf Woman…
在母狼身上办事
on a Woman Wolf.
但索尔唯一的真爱是地球女人珍芳达
But Thor's one true love was an Earth woman named Jane Fonda.
不对 珍佛斯特
Wait. No. Jane Foster.
可惜在爱的战役中 索尔输了
But sadly, in the battle for love, Thor lost.
其实那段时间他失去许多人
In fact, he lost a lot of people in those days.
他的老母
His mum.
他的老爸
His dad.
那个人
And that guy.
那个路人甲
And whoever that is.
还有海姆达尔
And Heimdall.
以及他的弟弟
And his brother.
然后又是他的弟弟
And his brother, again.
又是他
And again.
可怜的索尔看着他的星球爆炸
Poor Thor had to watch his planet explode.
然后他说：「我做了什么？」
And then he said, "What have I done?"
他爱的一切和每个人似乎都没了
It seemed that everything and everyone he loved, he lost.
于是他把心藏在庞大的肉身里
And so he hid his heart behind a big, fleshy bod…
这样心就不会再破碎了
so it could never be broken again.
就算他不再爱 不代表不再战斗
But just because he was done loving, didn't mean he was done fighting.
他与星际异攻队合体
He teamed up with the Guardians of the Galaxy…
展开经典的索尔大冒险
and set off on some classic Thor adventures.
他恢复健美体态
He got in shape.
拚命锻炼肌肉
Putting in the hard yards.
将痛苦化为动力 丝毫不偷懒
Turning pains into gains, and never skipping leg day.
他从肥肉老爹变成筋肉男神
He went from Dad Bod to God Bod.
但在男神的外表下 还有悲伤的情绪
But beneath his God Bod, there was still a Sad Bod…
想要尽情释放
just trying to get out.
因为索尔多年来操练的肉身
Because all of the bods that Thor had worn over the years…
都隐藏不了他内心的痛苦
couldn't hide the pain that he was feeling on the inside.
于是他放弃寻找爱
So he gave up his search for love…
接受自己只擅长一件事
accepting that he was only good for one thing…
静静沉思 等着有人问
Waiting in quiet contemplation for someone to say…
「索尔 我们要你帮忙打赢这场仗」
"Thor, we need your help to win this battle."
索尔
Thor.
我们要你帮忙打赢这场仗
We need your help to win this battle.
我们走
Let's go.
好 走吧 风暴破坏者
Okay. Come on, Stormbreaker.
继续上工
Back to work.
我们得赶快
We must hurry, okay?
很多人危在旦夕
People are dying.
下面见
See you down there.
动作快
Hurry up!
给我 你会弄坏的
Give me those. You're gonna break 'em.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot!
上面都是你的树汁
You got sap all over it.
- 大家好　- 唉呀 看是谁来了
- Hello, everybody. - Well, well, look who it is.
大家混得还好吗？
How are we doing, guys?
烂透了
Terrible!
我们都快死了
We're all about to die.
你说这星球是悠闲的度假村
You said this planet would be a relaxing holiday.
我说它会「像个悠闲的度假村」
I said it was going to be, "Like a relaxing holiday."
看看灿烂的天空 三个土星的太阳
But look at that resplendent skyscape. Three suns of Saturn.
有什么比这更悠闲的？
What could be more relaxing than that?
真正的度假村
An actual holiday!
布斯肯废渣去死吧
Die Booskan scum!
雷霆之神
God of Thunder.
亚坎王
King Yakan.
你终于加入我们的战役
You have finally joined our fight.
俗话说 迟到总比不到好
Well, as they say, "Better late than not at all."
非常好
Yes, it's very nice.
你也知道 我们曾住在和平的绿洲
As you know, we used to live in a peaceful oasis.
- 接着我们的神惨遭杀害　- 杀害？
- But then our gods were murdered. - Murdered?
如今我们的圣殿无人守护
And now our sacred temple has been left unguarded…
哈布斯卡的党羽掌控了它的力量
and Habooska's hordes took control of its power.
那是我们最神圣的殿堂 他亵渎了它
It is our most sacred shrine and he desecrates it.
嚣张没有落魄的久
Not for long.
亚坎王 跟他们说今天这里发生的事
King Yakan, tell them what happened here today.
告诉他们索尔…
Tell of the time that Thor…
和乌合之众组成的三流杂牌军
and his ragtag, motley crew of misfit desperados…
扭转了战争的局势
turned the tide of the battle…
让自己名留青史
and etched their names in history.
情势对我们不利 但我告诉你们
For the odds may be against us, but I'll tell you this for free…
来了
Here it comes.
此时此刻做个了断
This ends here and now!
他不会进入圣殿吧？不
He's not going to go into the temple, is he? No.
非常好 各位
Well done, everybody.
我们全体有功 因为我们团结一心
We can collectively take credit for that because we worked as a team.
我们用心和意志击败敌人
We used our hearts and our minds to defeat the enemy…
将损失降至最低
with minimal loss or damage.
经典的索尔大冒险
What a classic Thor adventure!
万岁！
Hurrah!
（佛斯特时空旅行理论）
好看吗？
Good book?
好看
Yeah.
我写的
I wrote it.
你是珍佛斯特博士？
Wait. You're Dr. Jane Foster?
我是
I am.
- 你好　- 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
爱因斯坦罗森桥怎么样？
How's the Einstein-Rosen Bridge?
很难懂
It's tough.
- 对　- 难到爆
- Yeah. - Really tough.
你需要一个3D模型
It's… You need a 3D model.
看过《撕裂地平线》吗？
You ever see Event Horizon?
没有
No.
- 《星际效应》？　- 没有
- Interstellar? - No.
那部片解释得很清楚
That movie explains everything really clearly.
好 爱因斯坦罗森桥
All right. The Einstein-Rosen Bridge…
折迭空间 所以A点和B点
folds space, so that point A and point B…
并存在时空中
coexist in space and time.
像这样
Like that.
你弄坏了自己的书
You just ruined your own book.
但现在你懂虫洞了
Yeah, but now you understand wormholes.
去找那些电影来看
Watch those movies.
- 好　- 好
- Okay. - Okay.
看到辣味芝多司 非买不可
Saw the Hot Cheetos, had to get it.
最近怎么样？
So, how's it going?
好得不得了
It's going amazing.
除了我 有告诉别人吗？
Have you told anyone else besides me?
别人发现就会开始怪怪的 变得不一样
When people find out they start acting weird. They're just different.
我现在不需要承受那些
I don't need that in my life right now.
反正没那么严重
Anyway, it's not that serious.
珍 你是第四期
Jane, it's Stage Four.
总共有几期？
Out of, like, how many stages?
四期
Four.
那是我们知道的
That we know about.
你要赶去哪个地方
Oh, you have somewhere else you gotta be right now…
比化疗更重要吗？
that's more important than chemo?
没有
No.
你想溜回实验室喔？
You're trying to get back to the lab, aren't you?
我有几个想法要试试看
I have a few ideas I'm trying.
不行 少来
Okay, no, time out.
我知道你想做实验室的工作
I know you think your lab work is something you have to do…
否则会让整个文明世界失望
otherwise you're letting down all of civilization…but.
你没搞懂宇宙想给你的讯息
you're not getting what the universe is actually trying to tell you…
我翻译给你听
so let me translate.
放慢脚步
Slow down.
你需要体力才能抗癌
You need your energy to fight this thing.
我会用自己的方式抗癌
I'll fight it my way, okay?
告诉你
Well, FYI…
自己的方式不等于单独待在实验室
"my way" does not have to equal alone in a lab.
或许你该打出太空维京人牌了
Maybe it's time to play the Space Viking card.
那不算一张牌
It's not a card.
就是
Yes, it is.
- 哪有什么牌　- 明明有
- There's no card. - There's a card.
高大金发又俊美
It's tall, it's blond, and it's gorgeous.
帅到掉渣牌
It's a handsome card.
- 珍 你确定吗？　- 黛西
- Jane, are you sure? - Look, Darcy…
我会自己想清楚
I will figure this out by myself.
（姓名：珍佛斯特）
检验结果还是一样
Results are still coming back the same.
化疗看来效果有限
I'm afraid the chemo has very little effect.
很遗憾 珍
I'm so sorry, Jane.
如果需要帮忙或想聊聊 打给我
If there's anything I can do, or if you just wanna talk, call me.
（维京神话）
（雷神之锤是）
（给他们）
（耐力与精神）
（良好健康）
（欢迎光临新阿斯加德 减速慢行）
（滕斯贝格）
（新阿斯加德之旅）
散发王者气息 因为你值得
Smell like a king, because you're worthy.
欧仕派
Old Spice.
卡！
Cut!
（无限寻宝乐园）
看看这里 好美
Look at this place. It's beautiful.
家
Home.
是的 家 父亲
Yes, home, Father.
我们是来带你回家的
We're here to take you home.
对 回到阿斯加德星
Yes. To planet Asgard.
阿斯加德不是星球 儿子
Asgard is not a planet, my sons.
它是一个民族 是你们
It is people. It is you!
现在 是我进入灵界的时候了
And now, it is time for me to pass on to the spirit realm.
我将进驻…
I will take my place…
英灵殿的大宴会厅
in the great banqueting hall of Valhalla…
众神的安息地
the resting place of the gods.
还有一件事
Oh, one more thing.
你们有个姊姊
You have a sister.
现在 我要变成神仙星尘
And so now, I turn into godly stardust…
与你们道别
and say farewell.
你们看
Oh, look.
看到没？开始了
Do you see? It's happening.
我消失了
I'm disappearing.
不！
No!
父王！
Father!
等等 哥
But wait! Brother!
我们身后出现一个不祥的入口
An ominous portal hath appeared behind us.
变身
Transform!
我是海拉 死亡女神
I am Hela, Goddess of Death.
我回到阿斯加德
Now, I return to Asgard.
夺回王位继承人头衔
to stake my claim as the rightful heir to the throne…
谁都阻止不了我
and no one will stop me!
不屈服就受死
Join me or die!
我们绝不屈服 女巫…雷神凸锤
We will never join you, witch! Mjolnir!
不可能
Impossible!
我摧毁了你的锤子
I broke your hammer!
受死吧
Time to die!
彩虹桥
Bifrost!
你几乎能感受到
You can almost feel the power…
这些美丽静止石头的力量
of these magnificent and immovable stones.
好 我们回村里去
Okay. Let's head back to the village…
喝点正宗的阿斯加德蜂蜜酒
where we can drink some real Asgardian mead.
走吧
Come on.
灾难之神
God of Disaster…
我们感谢你
we thank you.
我们担心少了
We feared we would be at war forever.
众神保护将永无宁日
without the protection of our gods…
但现在 和平将降临
but now, peace shall reign.
为报答你的恩情 请接受这些赠礼
In return for your service, please accept these gifts.
依照传统
As is tradition,
世界的保护者能获赠猛兽
the protectors of our world are bestowed with great beasts.
超级巨羊
Giant goats!
你看看 太棒了
Look at those! They are wonderful.
寇格 你看 它们真漂亮
Korg, look at that. Those things are beautiful.
亚坎王 太谢谢你了
King Yakan, thank you so much.
听着 关于圣殿…
Listen, about the temple…
我不想谈圣殿
I don't wanna talk about the temple.
我瞭 但如果要谈…
I know, but if we were to talk about it, I think it's important…
- 我会难过　- 对生命和物品…
- It's making me sad. - …to life and material objects…
- 很火大　- 我不说了
- And mad. - Okay, I'll stop talking.
别忘了羊
Don't forget the goats.
你接受了 就得带走
Which you accepted, and now must take with you.
恕不退货
No backsies.
- 它们真漂亮　- 对 很漂亮
- They are beautiful. - Yes, they are beautiful.
也很爱鬼叫
They also scream quite a lot.
没事的
They'll be fine.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
找到遥控器才能下载求救信号
We need to find the damn remote so we can download the distress signal!
回想一下 你把遥控器放哪？
Retrace your steps. Where did you put the remote?
大概被你的羊吃掉了
One of your goats probably ate it!
羊没吃遥控器 别鬼扯淡
Goats didn't eat the remote. Don't be ridiculous.
我才不伸进去找
Well, I ain't digging through their crap.
我爱它们 它们应该永远陪着我们
I love them! They should live with us forever!
找到遥控器了
Found the remote!
我来解决它们
I'm putting them down.
- 我也来　- 能不能用？
- Me too. - Is it working or not?
没用 没充电
No, it's not workin'. It's not charged.
- 也许你该找充电器　- 让开
- Well, maybe you need to find a charger… - Get out of my way!
喂…
Hey, hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa! Whoa, whoa!
- 寇格 没事吧？　- 我很好
- Korg, you okay? - Yeah, bro. All good.
大家放轻松 羊儿不碍事
All right. Everybody, just relax. The goats are gonna be fine.
不然也能拿来烤…
If not, we can just use them for meat…
考验智慧
…ting people.
考验智慧 看谁最懂动物
Meeting people. They're a great conversation starter.
听说吹特殊的口哨能召唤它们
And I've been told you can summon them with a special whistle…
这样吹
that goes something like this…
不对…
No, that's not it. No, that's not it.
不对 你吹吹看
No, that's not it. You have a go.
不对
No, that's not it.
- 大家好　- 克雷林
- Oh, hey, guys. - Kraglin!
不对
No, that's not it.
- 你一直在这里？　- 你叫我待在船上
- You been here this whole time? - Yeah, you said to stay with the ship.
这是格兰达 我们结婚了
This is Glenda. We're married.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我们是怎么说新恋情的？
What did we tell you about jumpin' into new relationships?
我不应该谈恋爱
That I shouldn't be doing that.
对 不能每到新的星球就结婚
Yeah, you can't get married on every single planet we land on.
（求救信号）
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
终于
Finally!
好 求救信号
All right, here we go. Distress calls.
请救救我们 屠神者发现我们了
Please help us! The God Butcher has found us!
屠神者？
God Butcher?
他吊死他们 当成警告
He left them hanging as a warning.
这些神惨遭杀害
Look at all of these gods, murdered.
我们最优秀的战士如今成了亡魂
Our greatest champions, now laid to waste.
好恐怖
The horror.
谁会下这种毒手？
Who could have done something like this?
索尔 你在哪里？
Thor, where are you?
等等 那是什么？回去
Wait, wait, wait. What was that? Go back.
播放那个
Play that one.
- 索尔 你在哪里？　- 希芙？
- Thor, where are you? - Sif?
我们需要你
We need you here.
我朋友有危险 得立刻赶过去
My friend is in danger. We must go at once.
发动船只 朋友们
Start the ship, my friends.
也许我们该分头行动
I don't know, maybe we should split up.
好多人要救 看这些求救…
So many people to save, I mean, look at all of these distress…
信号
calls.
索尔
Thor.
你不会有事吧？
You gonna be okay?
我欣赏你们对彼此的承诺 很感人
I admire your commitment to each other. It's a beautiful thing.
那是我永远不会有的
Alas, it's something I'll never have.
兄弟 听我说两句
Buddy, if I may…
你说
You may.
活了几千年
After thousands of years of living,
你似乎不了解自己
you don't seem to know who the hell you are.
我以前也迷惘过
I've been lost before.
后来我发现了意义 发现爱
But then I found meaning, I found love.
失去之后真的好痛
And yeah, it got taken from me, and god, that hurts.
但那种糟糕的感觉总比空虚好
But that shitty feeling is better than feeling empty.
希望你有一天能找到一样东西
My hope for you is that one day you will find something…
让你觉得这么糟糕
to make you feel this shitty.
我曾经爱过 却没有结果
I have loved before. It didn't work out.
她们不是惨死
They either die a grismal death.
就是写信把我甩了
or they dump you with a handwritten letter.
我不知道哪种比较惨
I don't know which is worse,
所以我才跟人保持距离
but it's why I keep everyone at arm's length.
你跟我太亲近了 我就知道会这样
You've grown too attached. Damn it, I knew this would happen.
你该走了 我去找希芙
You must go. I'll find Sif.
你们响应其他信号 星际需要异攻队
You answer the other calls. The galaxy needs its Guardians.
- 好 我们离…　- 我知道很痛
- Cool, yeah. We were just leaving… - I know it hurts.
但这样比较好 相信我
But it's better this way. You have to trust me.
为了抚平伤痛 干脆你们…
To ease the pain, why don't you…
开走这艘船 当成临别礼物？
take this ship here as a parting farewell gift?
你要把我的船送给我？
You're giving me my ship?
对 它是你的了
Yes, she's yours.
愿你跟我一样与它创造许多回忆
May you make as many memories with her as I have.
它脾气别扭
She's a temperamental old lass.
危急时尽忠职守
Will serve you well in a tight pickle.
- 我来发动　- 谢谢
- I'll start the ship. - Thank you.
再见 老朋友
Goodbye, old friend.
人类的握手
A human handshake…
变成阿斯加德式握手
to the Asgardian shake.
变成你不能相信的蛇
Into the snake that you cannot trust.
拖太久尴尬了
You're really dragging this out.
最后变成经典的阿斯加德击指
And finish with the classic Asgardian high one.
走吧
Let's go.
照顾我的队员 他们会很辛苦
Take care of my crew. This is gonna be hard for them.
动作快
Hurry up!
她不用
Not her.
记住我的话
Remember what I told you.
如果感到迷惘
You ever feel lost…
就看着心爱之人的双眸
just look into the eyes of the people that you love.
它们会让你知道自己是谁
They'll tell you exactly who you are.
好 掰
All right. Bye.
无论如何 珍惜美好的回忆
For what it's worth, let's cling to the good memories.
我们阿斯加德人都说 「愿你旅行快如奥丁渡鸦
We Asgardians say, "May you travel with the speed of Odin's ravens.
我们英灵殿见 畅饮蜂蜜酒…」
"I'll see you in Valhalla where we shall drink mead and…"
- 他们走了　- 又落单了 只剩你和我
- They're gone. - Alone again. Just me and you.
风暴破坏者
Stormbreaker!
小心 臭斧头
Watch out, you frickin' crazy axe!
现在怎么办 兄弟？
So what do we do now, bro?
我们去找希芙
Let's go get Sif!
那是什么东东？
Who or what is that?
法利加 法利加人之神
Falligar, God of the Falligarians.
会是你见过最善良的神
One of the nicest gods you'll ever meet.
糟糕
Oh, no.
希芙 是我 索尔
Sif, it's me, Thor.
奥汀森？
Odinson?
你少了一只手臂
You're missing an arm.
我带你回家
I'm gonna get you home.
不 让我留在这里
No! Leave me here.
我想以战士之姿死去
I want to die a warrior's death.
死在战场上 战死沙场
On the battlefield. In battle.
那我就能入祀英灵殿
And then I can claim my place in Valhalla.
我实在不想吐槽
Oh, I hate to break it to you…
战士入祀英灵殿 必须战死沙场
but for a warrior to get into Valhalla, you have to die in the battle.
- 你没死　- 靠
- You survived. - Oh, shit.
说不定你的手臂在英灵殿
Maybe your arm is in Valhalla.
出了什么事？
What happened here?
我在追捕一个狂人
I've been hunting a madman.
跟踪他到这里 但这是陷阱
I followed him here, but it was a trap.
那个狂人是谁？
Who is this madman?
屠神者来了
The God Butcher is coming.
他企图歼灭众神
He seeks the extinction of the gods.
阿斯加德是他下一个目标
Asgard is next.
（枪与玫瑰 九界）
（大色拉 摇滚节）
看 是索尔
Look, it's Thor!
- 索尔　- 带希芙去医务室
- Thor! - Take Sif to the infirmary.
喂！
Hey!
你惹毛了谁？
Who'd you piss off now?
不是我的错 我没见过这些玩意
This is not my fault. I've never even seen these things…
谁晓得它们是什么
whatever the hell they are.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
那个新来的是谁？
Who's the new guy?
那个吗？你会很喜欢他
That guy? You're gonna love that guy.
雷神之锤…
Mjolnir! Mjolnir!
是我 索尔
It's me, Thor.
有看到我的锤子吗？
Have you seen my hammer?
雷神之锤 在这里
Mjolnir, here, boy.
雷神之锤？
Mjolnir?
雷神之锤
Mjolnir.
你回来了
You're back!
雷神之锤
Mjolnir!
不好意思
Excuse me.
你好 你拿的是我的锤子
Hello. That's my hammer you've got there.
那是我的造型
And that's my look.
喂！
Hey!
别耍白痴了
Enough tomfoolery.
拿下面具 露个脸吧？
Why don't you take off that mask and reveal yourself?
快点
Come on.
嗨
Hey.
珍？
Jane?
让我告诉你们索尔与珍的传奇
Let me tell you the legend of Thor and Jane.
他是雷霆之神 她是女科学家
He was a God of Thunder and she, a woman of science.
虽然他们来自不同的世界
And although they were from different worlds…
却还是走在一起
somehow, it just made sense.
他们共同展开一段爱的旅程
And together they embarked on a journey of love.
索尔教导珍战士之道
Thor taught Jane the way of the warrior…
珍教索尔为人之道
And Jane taught Thor the way of the people.
时光飞逝 他们的爱越来越深
And as time passed, their love grew deeper and deeper.
她很棒吧 雷神之锤？
She's incredible, isn't she, Mjolnir?
我要你答应我 永远保护她
I need you to promise me you'll always protect her.
我也爱你 兄弟
I love you too, buddy.
那么深刻的爱产生了魔力
And love that deep has a way of becoming magical.
索尔开始规划未来
Thor set his sights toward a future…
想象往后的日子
and all it might hold.
他越思考与珍的生活
But the more he pondered a life with Jane,
就越怕失去它
the more he feared losing that life.
尽管珍不想承认
And although Jane didn't want to admit it…
她也担心失去这些
she was scared of loss as well.
于是两人之间出现隔阂
And so, they built walls between them.
（尼克福瑞）
索尔忙着拯救人类
Thor got busy saving humanity.
海姆达尔
Heimdall!
珍也忙着做同样的事
And Jane got busy doing the same.
真的很忙
Real busy.
最后两人渐行渐远
And eventually, the space between them grew and grew.
难以弥补
until it became too wide to bear.
终究得有所取舍
Something had to give.
我必须熬通宵才能跑完数据
I have to stay up all night to go through this data. Okay?
我整晚不睡才能清理干净
And I have to stay up all night and clean all of this up.
- 才两个盘子　- 两个盘子和两根叉子
- There's two plates! - It's two plates and two forks!
某天晚上 有人做出了取舍
And then, one night, it did give.
珍写了一张字条
Jane wrote a note.
索尔看了
And Thor read that note.
他们的传奇顿时成了神话
And their legend suddenly became myth.
至少他们那么以为
Or so they thought.
你还好吗？
You okay?
还好 有点热…
Yeah, it's a little hot in…
我开始觉得…
Startin' to feel…
头盔让人幽闭恐惧症发作
It's claustrophobic with the helmet.
怎么可能？
How?
能晚点再谈吗？
Can we talk about this later?
好啊
Yeah, sure.
很高兴见到你
Great seeing you.
什么？
What?
屠杀众神
Kill all the gods.
嘿 这是死灵剑吗？
Hey. Is that the Necrosword?
超酷 我只在故事里读过
That's cool. I've only ever read about it in stories.
那你就知道这会很痛
Then you know this is going to hurt.
痛苦
Pain.
痛苦不过是弱者发明的概念
What is pain but a construct invented by the weak?
好啦 非常利
Okay, that's very sharp!
准备好了吗？
Ready?
别碰我的东西
Don't touch my things.
你最好快跑 孬种
Yeah, you better run, you coward.
孩子 它们带走孩子了
The children. They're taking the children!
妈咪
Mommy!
妈
Mom!
阴影怪物 恶心
Shadow monsters. Disgusting.
绕行世界两圈 没找到
Flew around the world twice. Nothing.
那些孬种一定跑了 我们会找到它们
Cowards must have run away. We'll find them.
- 好特别的重逢方式　- 就是啊
- Quite a reunion, huh? - You're telling me.
多久了？三、四年？
What's it been? Like, three, four years?
八年七个月又六天
Eight years, seven months, and six days.
我没忘记…
I haven't forgotten…
上次看到你 或没看到你 你离开了
the last time I saw you, or didn't see you, because you left.
说我离开是过度简化了
It's kind of an oversimplification to say that I left.
不 你离开了 真的
No, you left. You did.
你手写了一封优美的信
You wrote me a beautiful handwritten letter.
我知道 我在场
I should know, I was there.
- 你不在 所以我才写　- 我在
- You weren't there, actually, hence the note. - I was.
若你没看到我离开 或许离开的是你
And if you weren't there to see me leave, then maybe it was you that left.
有道理
Fair point.
那不重要啦
Not that it matters.
- 有谁在记这些？　- 对啊
- Like, who's keeping track, right? - No, yeah.
我们都离开 也被离开
I suppose we both left and both got left.
现在你又离开了
Now you're leaving again.
米克 我们需要所有证人的详尽说词
Miek, we need detailed accounts from all the witnesses.
戴洛 给我失踪孩童的名单
Darryl, get me all the names of the children who have been lost.
陛下 我女儿被带走 下落不明
Your Majesty, my daughter has been taken, and I don't know where she is.
会找到她的
And she'll be found.
各位 他们流血了 快带去医务室
Guys, they're bleeding. Get them to the infirmary. Now!
戴洛
Darryl!
陛下 该筹备这场混乱的戏码吗？
Majesty, should we start working on a performance of this entire debacle?
人民需要娱乐
The people need entertainment.
尤其在这危机当头之时
Particularly now, in times of crisis.
尤其这时候
Particularly.
我没听到她说不行
I did not hear a, "No."
我也没听到
Nor did I.
- 阿斯加德 夜景　- 对
- Asgard. Night. - Yes!
开场是孩子在睡觉
We open on some sleeping children.
那是你前女友吧？
So, that's the ex-girlfriend, is it?
熟悉的前女友
The old ex-girlfriend.
茱蒂佛斯特
Jodie Foster.
珍佛斯特
Jane Foster.
有缘无份的那个
The one that got away.
那代表逃离
That means escaped.
是啊…
Yeah. Yeah… Yeah.
看到前女友和前锤子相处融洽
Must be hard for you to see your ex-girlfriend…
你一定不好受
and your ex-hammer hangin' out, and getting on so well.
你在干嘛？
What you up to, bro?
过来
Come on.
过来找把拔
Come to daddy.
过来 雷神之锤
Come on. Mjolnir.
嘿 你出现了
Hey! There you are.
嘿
Hey.
- 知道我的想法吗？　- 我刚刚呼唤你
- Do you know what I think we should do? - I was just calling you.
- 组军队　- 怎么组？一半士兵都死了
- Start an army! - With what? Half our soldiers are dead!
我们总是有一半士兵死掉
Half our soldiers are always dead!
- 各位 拜托…　- 孩子们呢？
- Everyone, please… - Where are the children?
回家去 我保证很快就有消息
…go home. I promise you we'll have news soon.
该有人告诉我们怎么回事
Someone needs to tell us what happened.
我们会找到他们
We shall find them.
- 我不懂　- 你知道吗？
- I just don't understand. - You know what?
这都是我们的错
This is all our fault.
住手
Stop it!
阿斯加德
Asgard!
朋友 我们千万别争吵
My friends, we must not quarrel.
这时候我们需要团结一致
In times like this, we need to unite, come together.
我明白这里的状况
I see what's happening here.
你们害怕
You're afraid.
担忧
Scared.
害怕
Afraid.
焦虑
Anxious.
如果要找到孩子 得先深刻自省
If we are to find the children, we must first look within ourselves.
米克 振奋人心的演说不要出怪声
I'm sorry. Miek, it's very hard to give a rousing speech with the… noise.
- 你在干嘛？　- 她在做会议纪录
- What are you doing? - She's taking minutes.
没时间做纪录
Precious minutes we don't have.
你们要孩子回来？
You want the kids back?
我马上回来
I'll be back in a minute.
把这写下来 米克
You can write that down, Miek.
不
No!
风暴破坏者 你在干嘛 因为雷神之锤吗？
Stormbreaker, what are you doing? Is this about Mjolnir?
通通出去
Everyone, out!
没找到他们
Didn't find them.
你的披风着火了
Bae, your cape's on fire.
没关系 它会长回来
It's fine. It'll grow back.
我会开发票给你
I'm invoicing you for this.
听着
Listen.
我们对这家伙了解多少？
What do we know about this guy?
- 他在阴影间移动　- 用阴影创造怪兽
- He travels through shadows. - And he creates monsters with them.
奇特无比的怪兽
Absolutely freaky monsters.
他还使用死灵剑 我怎么知道呢？
He also wields the Necrosword. How do I know that?
他差点刺中我的脸
Because he almost speared me in the face with it.
死灵剑是什么？
What's a Necrosword?
自开天辟地就传承下来的
It's an ancient weapon that's been passed through hands.
古老武器
since the dawn of time.
它具有杀神的能力
It has the ability to slay gods…
慢慢腐蚀与杀害持有者 也就是…
but it slowly corrupts and kills whoever wields it, which means…
- 所以它影响了他　- 对 一定是
- So, it infected him. - It's infecting him. Yes. It must be.
所以基本上我们对付的是
So basically, we're up against a cursed,
一个受诅咒的阴影丧尸绑匪
shadow-zombie kidnapper.
好棒棒 何时出发？
Awesome. When do we leave?
索尔
Thor.
你看得见我吗？
Can you see me?
出现漂浮头
Floating head alert.
是阿斯翠 海姆达尔的儿子
It's Astrid. Heimdall's son.
阿斯翠 你还好吗？
Astrid, are you okay?
我已经不叫阿斯翠了
I no longer go by the name Astrid.
我现在叫艾克索
I'm now known as Axl.
他是地球一个热门乐团的主唱
He's a singer from a popular band I heard on Earth.
- 枪与玫瑰　- 阿斯翠
- G N' R. - Astrid…
你父亲给你一个强悍的维京名字
your father gave you a very tough Viking name…
我要实现他的心愿
and I intend to honor his wishes.
- 艾克索　- 阿斯翠
- Axl. - Astrid.
- 我说艾克索　- 阿斯翠
- I said Axl. - Astrid.
- 艾克索　- 艾你的头 听他说
- Axl! - It's asshole. Now listen to him!
好 艾克索 你在哪里？
All right, fine, Axl. Where are you?
不清楚 我还不会用我的魔眼
I'm not sure. I don't know how to use my magic eyes yet.
你父亲教过我 我能教你
Your father taught me and I'm gonna teach you.
现在集中精神 伸出你的手
I need you to focus and hold out your hand.
很好 专心
Okay, good. Now focus.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
索尔
Thor!
你们好吗 小朋友？
Hey, how's it going, kids?
我们好吗？看看我们在哪
"How's it going?" Look where we are.
我们关在钉子做成的笼子里
We're in a cage made of spikes.
对 不好
Yes, right. Not good. Yeah.
你能拿出办法吗？
Are you gonna do something?
我会 但不是现在
Yes. Yes, I am, but just not right now.
我是个幻影 你看
I'm the vision ghost. Look.
- 有没有？　- 我们会怎样？
- See? - What will happen to us?
谁晓得？情况十分不妙
Who can tell? I mean, this is a very, very bad situation.
好消息是 你们是阿斯加德人
You know, the good news is you're Asgardians.
如果死了 你们都会进英灵殿
So, if you die, you'll end up in Valhalla.
天啊 走开啦
Oh, my God. Go away.
等等 听我说
Wait, wait. Listen.
没事 小朋友 别哭 没事
Okay. It's all right, children. Don't cry. Don't cry. It's okay.
我有个计划
Listen, I've got a plan, okay?
我会集结一支菁英部队
I'm putting together a really, really good team.
我们有寇格叔叔 瓦尔基丽王
We've got Uncle Korg, King Valkyrie…
我前女友珍
my ex-girlfriend, Jane,
我们的情史就不说了
which is a whole other story I won't bore you with, okay?
这是一支顶尖部队
But it is a top-notch team…
我们很快就带你们回家
and we're gonna have you home before you know it.
对
Yeah.
我知道你们在哪
I know where you are.
我会带你们离开
I'm gonna get you out of here.
我好怕 我们都好怕
I'm scared. We all are.
索尔…救救我们
Thor! Thor! Save us.
让我离开 你们保重
Get me out of here. You take care, okay?
你们保重 我们很快会见面
Take care. I'll see you soon. All right?
艾克索 让我离开
Axl, get me out of here!
他们在暗影领域
They're in the Shadow Realm.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
那里的浓重大气有种独特的黑暗
The heavy atmosphere there has a darkness like no other.
彷佛色彩不敢涉足 很容易辨认
It's as if color fears to tread. It's unmistakable.
那如果我们需要色彩
Well then, if it's color we need…
就带彩虹过去
let's bring the rainbow.
带彩虹过去？这是口号吗？
"Bring the rainbow"? Is that a catchphrase or something?
她刚当雷神没多久
She's only been a Thor for a minute.
救人她很会
I mean, saving lives, she's quite good at.
其余的有待改进
But the rest of it, she needs work.
- 总共有几个口号？　- 很多
- How many catchphrases have there been? - A lot.
对 我操之过急
Yep. Jumped the gun.
等等
Hang on,
他穿越黑影要去暗影领域
he moves through shadows and he's going to the Shadow Realm…
他到了那里似乎会威力无穷
it seems like that's where he's going to be the most powerful.
对 不能冒然前往 可能是陷阱
You're right. We can't just go marching in there. It could be a trap.
我们会危及小朋友
We'd be endangering the children.
我们需要援军 必须召集军队
We need reinforcements. We must raise an army.
你在想我在想你在想的吗？
Are you thinking what I think you're thinking?
- 我在想　- 我们在想什么？
- I'm thinking it. - What are we thinking?
- 想什么？　- 我也在想
- Thinking what? - I'm thinking it too.
全知之城
Omnipotence City.
全知之城是什么？
What's Omnipotence City?
宇宙最强众神的所在地
It's the home of the most powerful gods in the universe.
我们能组成史上最强团队
We could pull together the greatest team ever.
召集埃及太阳神、海格力斯
We could recruit Ra, Hercules…
毛利战神
Tūmatauenga.
羽蛇神 还有最老最有智慧的宙斯
Quetzalcoatl, maybe. And Zeus, the oldest and wisest of them all.
你说宙斯？
Did you say Zeus?
对 宙斯
Yeah, Zeus.
宙斯 那个宙斯？
Like, the Zeus. Zeus-Zeus?
我不知道他有没有小名
I'm not sure if he has a second name.
我的神会在那里吗？尼尼诺尼？
Do you think my god will be there, Ninny of the Nonny?
很难说 在的话就请他们加入
You never know, Korg. But if they are, we'll ask them to join our team.
赞
Yes.
风暴破坏者
Stormbreaker.
好 冷静 放轻松
All right. Calm down. Relax.
我们不靠风暴破坏者的烂彩虹桥旅行
No, no, no, mate, we are not traveling in Stormbreaker's janky Bifrost.
看看刚刚的状况
Look what just happened.
不能骑你的迷你飞天入口马吧？
We can't exactly go in your tiny, little, flying portal horse, can we?
载不下
We won't all fit.
你在说什么？战歌超赞的
What are you talking about? Warsong's awesome.
风暴破坏者也很赞
Stormbreaker's awesome too.
风暴破坏者需要通道
Stormbreaker just needs a conduit.
能进行太空旅行的东西
Anything that can handle space travel.
我喜欢她聊正事的样子
I love it when she talks shop.
它有能力带我们过去
It has the power to get us there…
但要有东西集中能量 以免出状况
it just needs something to focus that energy so it's not so unpredictable.
如果有一艘能驾驭的船
You know, if we had a ship we could harness it…
可用风暴破坏者当能源
and use Stormbreaker as a power source.
- 就像引擎　- 就像引擎
- Oh, like an engine. - Like an engine.
你需要船？
You need a ship?
我有船
I've got a ship.
把座位全部移走
Get rid of all those seats.
你们把羊绑在前面
And you guys, go tie those goats to the front.
15分钟后出发
We leave in 15 minutes.
只带必需品 各位
Essentials only, everyone.
那是必需品
That's essential.
15分钟后启程
Fifteen minutes to departure!
这么快就找到新欢啦？
Well, you moved on quick, didn't you?
真有你的
You're some piece of work.
- 嗨　- 嗨
- Oh, hey! - Hey.
- 我在跟老朋友叙旧　- 嗯
- Just catching up with an old friend. - Yeah.
我一直想道歉
I've been meaning to apologize.
以前我有点怪
Sorta acting a little weird before.
不知道哪根筋不对
I just haven't really been myself lately.
就是…
You know, kind of…
想搞清楚自己是谁 有点迷惘
Trying to figure out who I am, and just felt a little bit lost.
接着突然看到你穿得跟我一样
And then, all of a sudden, I see you dressed as me…
有点…
and it was kind of…
我也很意外
It's a lot for me, too.
你们怎么凑在一块 怎么回事？
So, how did you guys get together? How did this happen?
我发誓我听到雷神之锤呼唤我
I swear I heard Mjolnir call to me.
是喔？
Ah, did it?
于是我来这里调查
And so I came here to investigate…
它的碎片开始发光 旋转…
and its pieces started glowing and swirling, and then…
好扯
Crazy.
我就成了雷神
…Thor.
这造型超适合你
Well, you know what, it looks good on you, it works, so…
确认一下
Just checking.
回头见
See you later.
5分钟后启程
Five minutes to departure!
怎样？
What?
我们聊天而已
We were just talking.
妈咪 不要离开我
Mommy, don't leave me.
不要怕
Don't be afraid.
即使我走了 亲爱的
Even when I'm gone, honey…
你不会孤单
You won't be alone.
（怀念伊莲佛斯特）
不管发生什么事
And whatever happens…
绝不停止奋斗
never stop fighting.
Never stop fighting.
嗨 你还好吗？
Hey. You all right?
好极了
Great.
洗脸盆露馅了
The sink would say otherwise.
你想我该去吗？
You think I really should be coming?
我身体越来越差
I'm not getting any better.
你是雷神 当然该去
You're a Thor. Of course, you should come.
不然你还能怎么做？
Besides, what else are you gonna do?
你现在是维京人了
You're a Viking now.
可以说必须战死沙场
Means you pretty much have to die in battle…
而且得痛苦得要命
and it needs to be devastatingly painful.
否则你进不了英灵殿
Otherwise, you don't get into Valhalla.
我是这么打算
That's my plan.
当国王的事怎么办？
What about, you know, kinging and stuff?
我喜欢当国王 我爱我的人民
I love being king. I love my people…
但整天开会 飞鸦传书
but it's all meetings and raven-mail…
还有飞鸦传书就能搞定的会议
and meetings that could've been raven-mail.
我想念打仗
I miss fighting.
想念我的姊妹
I miss my sisters.
所以你得去 我需要一个姊妹
Which is why you need to come, 'cause I need one.
好 该走了
Okay, we should go.
打包好了？
You packed?
你打包了吗？
Are you packed?
赞
Yes!
手榴弹？
A hand grenade?
不是 随身喇叭
No. It's a portable speaker.
走吧
Let's go.
洗脸盆的事你能保密吧？
If you don't mind keeping the sink thing under wraps?
我罩你
I got you.
我的阿斯加德同胞们
My fellow Asgardians…
愿我们旅行快如奥丁渡鸦
Wish us well, for we shall travel with the speed of Odin's ravens.
我们会把孩子们带回来
We will return with children.
许多孩子
Many children.
然后设宴庆祝
And then we shall feast!
不会吃小孩
Not on the children.
我们不干那种事了
We do not do that anymore.
那是黑暗的时代 羞耻的时代
Those were dark times. Shameful times.
好 出发
Okay, we should go.
还在溜直排轮吗？
So, you still rollerblading?
没有 你呢？
No. No. You?
有 每个周末
Oh, yeah. Every weekend.
溜了就停不下来 对吧 寇格？
Once you blade, you never fade. Right, Korg?
永远的直排轮伙伴
Skate mates for life!
- 我能说一件事吗？　- 好
- Hey, can I run something by you? - Yeah.
我在想…
So, I was thinking…
等我们找到坏蛋 我想喊个响亮口号
when we get to the bad guy, what about if I had, like, a cool catchphrase?
像是「吃我的锤子」
Like, "Eat this hammer!"
或是「瞧我的大锤」
Or, like, "Check out my hammer."
还是…
Like, what about…
不 我还在发想
No… I'm workshopping it.
这些都不错 我的口号是
No, they are all really good. Mine is…
「此时此刻做个了断」
"This ends here and now."
超赞的口号
Oh, that's such a good one.
我润饰了很久
Took me a long time to perfect it.
你可以的 只要多练习
You'll get there. You just need to practice.
他是我第一个坏蛋
Just my first bad guy.
第一个意难忘
You never forget your first.
是啊
Yeah.
你有女朋友吗？
So, you got a girlfriend?
没有 太忙了 没空
No, no. Too busy, don't have time, you know?
整天都在工作
Just the work and everything.
酷 我得查看一下这地方
Cool. Gonna check this place out.
好酷
So cool.
什么好酷？
Who's so cool?
这些建筑很酷
The buildings are cool.
- 刚刚是怎样？　- 什么？
- What's happening there? - Where?
好像有粉红泡泡
Am I sensing feelings?
粉红泡泡？跟珍吗？
Feelings? What, for Jane?
别乱讲
No, don't be ridiculous. Feelings.
上次我们有粉红泡泡是…
The last time we had feelings were…
很久以前 很久很久
long time ago. Long, long gone. I think you…
- 你才有粉红泡泡 - 是的
- Maybe you have feelings. - Right.
- 大哥 放轻松 我们同一国的 - 我不知道
- Mate, relax. We're on the same team. - I don't know.
我知道我们是哪一国的
Know exactly what team we're on, okay?
爱珍国
Team Jane.
索尔的优点就是能迅速恢复正常
Thing about Thor is that he always bounces back.
- 对　- 海拉偷走他的锤子时
- Yeah. - Like when Hela stole his hammer…
他就在垂死星球的核心打造斧头
he went and built an axe which was forged in the heart of a dying star.
那把斧头砍了萨诺斯的头
And the same axe was used to cut off Thanos' head.
真棒
That's a good one.
好精彩的故事
What a neat story!
聊了这么多砍头的事
With all this talk about chopping off heads…
害我手都痒了
I wanna have a go.
这是什么？
What's this?
这是阿弟 你好 阿弟
This is Octy. Hello, Octy.
你好吗？
How are you?
知道阿弟喜欢什么吗？
You know what Octy loves?
让它的头被扯断
Having his head ripped off!
你们刚刚还很喜欢啊
What? You liked it a second ago.
好啦…
All right, all right, all right.
阿弟走了
Octy's gone.
拜托
Come on.
我好怕
I'm scared.
看看你
Look at you.
我认识一个跟你一样的小女生
I knew a little girl just like you.
她很勇敢 很聪明
And she was brave, and she was smart…
又好玩 喜欢画画
and funny and she liked to draw.
我问你们一个问题
Let me ask you a question…
跟神有关
about gods.
祂们应该保护你们 对吧？
They're meant to protect you, right?
那祂们在哪呢？
Well, where are they?
- 索尔就快来了　- 对
- Thor is on his way. - Yeah!
对 我等着
Yes. I'm counting on that.
所以你们才在这里
That's why you're here.
限受邀者参加
It's invitation only,
我们低调混进去
so we're gonna have to keep a low profile and blend in.
幸好伪装是我的强项
Luckily, disguises are my specialty.
希腊哲学家？
Greek philosopher?
我弄来这些
Got us these.
这些是什么？
What are those?
真正的伪装
Actual disguises.
它们是情感众神的披风
They're the cloaks of the emotion gods.
每个颜色象征不同情绪
Every color signifies a different emotion.
情感众神在哪里？
Where are the emotion gods?
别问
Don't ask.
哇靠
Holy shit.
欢迎莅临黄金神殿
Welcome to the Golden Temple, kids.
这是宇宙最强造物神祇聚会的地方
This is where the most powerful creator gods in the universe hang out.
有魔力之神、梦之神
There's the god of magic, the god of dreams…
木工之神
the god of carpentry.
看看那个
Look at that one.
那是包子 饺子之神
Oh, yes. That's Bao, god of dumplings.
- 嗨 包子　- 包子
- Hey, Bao! - Bao.
你们看上面
Look up there, guys!
那是克罗南的神 尼尼诺尼
That's the Kronan god, Ninny of the Nonny.
嗨 尼尼诺尼
Hey, Ninny Nonny!
宙斯…
Zeus! Zeus! Zeus!
对
Yes.
我是宙斯
I am Zeus!
他来了
There he is!
伟人 神话 传奇
The man, the myth, the legend.
不晓得你知不知道
I don't know if you know this…
我很多地方都效法这个人
but I base a lot of what I do on this guy.
他是闪电之神 我是雷霆之神
He's the god of lightning, I'm the god of thunder.
- 给了我不少灵感　- 很好
- Huge source of inspiration. - That's really good.
请他支持军队时应该先提这点
You should lead with that when you ask him for an army.
我们怎么上去？用飞的吗？
How do we get up there? Do we just, like, fly?
不能在进场时打扰他
No, we can't interrupt him in the middle of an entrance.
他以进场浮夸出名的
He's famous for his entrances.
雷霆闪电…
Thunderbolt! Thunderbolt!
帅！
Yes!
宙斯
Zeus!
赞！雷霆闪电！
Yes! Thunderbolt!
维持秩序
Order.
Order!
安静！安静！
Silence! Silence!
我特此召开…
I hereby open…
这神圣的神祇大会
this holy council of the god.
我们有许多严肃的议题要讨论
Where we have many, many serious matter to be talk about.
例如
Such as…
今年的群交趴在哪里举行？
where are we going to hold this year's orgy?
他是认真的吗？
Is this guy for real?
我有点想吐
Honestly, I'm not mad at it.
我相信他有他的道理
Yeah, I'm sure he has a point, okay?
抱歉
Sorry.
现在宣布
So now we're going to announce the winner…
「以上帝之名牺牲最多人」的优胜者
of the, "Most human souls sacrificed in the name of a god."
也许他没那么棒
Okay, maybe he's not that great.
不 太糟了
Oh, no, not good.
我想再糟就这样了
No, I don't think it's gonna get any better than this.
这些神帮不上忙
Look, these gods aren't gonna help.
但那个雷霆闪电可能用得上
But that thunderbolt, I think that might be of use.
珍 你往右 索尔 你往左
Jane, you go right. Thor, you go left.
我们出其不备 抢走闪电
We bum-rush him, take the bolt, ding-dong.
- 我们去抢　- 不…等等
- All right, let's go get it! - No, no, no, wait!
不能用突袭的阴招
There's no ding-donging or bum-rushing.
尤其是对宙斯
Especially not Zeus' bum.
我找个适当时机跟他谈
When the time is right, I'm gonna talk to him.
现在就去
The time is right now.
现在不方便
Time is not right now.
谁在说话？
Who is talking?
- 这几个　- 寇格 闭嘴
- These guys. - Korg, shut up.
你们有话对大家说吗？
Do you have something to say to the group?
抱歉
Sorry.
我60秒后开扁 快说
I'm bashing heads in 60 seconds, so speak fast.
有人得受点教训
Literally, heads will roll.
你们吃错药啦？
Who are you two?
大家好
Hello.
我想先说非常荣幸能够…
Let me be the first to say it is an honor and a privilege to be…
我听不见
No, I can't hear you.
不如你上台吧？
Why don't you take the stage?
下面的舞台？
The stage down there?
对 你看很像舞台的那个区域？
Well, yes. You see the area that looks very much like a stage?
了解
Got ya.
借过
Coming through.
抱歉
Oops. Sorry.
祝你好运
Good luck, bro.
强大的宙斯
Mighty Zeus!
哇
Wow!
宇宙众神
Gods of the universe…
我是来求助 希望召集大军
I come here to ask for your help, to raise an army.
有个叫屠神者的疯子想杀光我们
There's a maniac called the God Butcher who seeks to end us all.
他到处烧杀掳掠
His destruction is everywhere.
众多星球、领域
Entire planets, realms…
都已陷入浩劫
have been left completely unprotected.
他造成灾难与混乱
He's left nothing but chaos in his wake.
但我知道他的下落
But I know where he is…
有各位的协助 我们能及早击溃他
and with your help we can crush him before he kills anyone else.
那个人
That guy…
他杀了几个低阶的神
he killed a couple of low-level god.
呜呼哀哉
Boo-hoo.
如果你讲完了
If that's all…
小鲜肉
pretty boy…
就回座乖乖闭嘴
you go back to your seat and you be quiet.
抱歉 你没听到我说的吗？
Yeah, I'm sorry. Did you not hear any of what I just said?
他大开杀戒
He's murdering en masse.
我跟你说过一次了
I tell you one time…
现在闭嘴
now, you shut up.
安静惦惦
You be quiet.
你就快无法受邀参加群交趴了
Because you are this close to being uninvited to the orgy.
宙斯 我们必须采取行动
Zeus, we must do something.
你不准参加群交趴
You cannot come to the orgy!
- 你得听我们的　- 够了
- You have to listen to us! - That's it!
上铐
Shackle!
陛下 你准备好就告诉我
Your Highness, whenever you're ready, you just tell me.
- 听我的指示　- 嗯哼
- We go on my signal. - Mm-hmm.
什么指示？
What is the signal?
我会说「上」
It'll be, "Go."
来看看你是何方神圣
Let's see who you are.
我要卸下你的伪装
I take off your disguise.
弹指神功！
And flick!
你弹太大力了 可恶
You flicked too hard, damn it!
（洛基安息）
我们该帮他吗？
Should we help him?
最后还是要
I mean, eventually.
吃葡萄？
Grape?
就像软趴趴的小胡瓜
Looks like a shy courgette.
另外那几个呢？
And what about the others?
把他们的伪装也卸了
We take off their disguise too.
不 别弹我们
Oh, no. No. Don't flick us.
不用了
It's cool.
伪装没了
Disguise gone!
拿掉了
Disguise off. Cool?
阿斯加德人
Asgardians.
我以为奥丁死后就不会见到你们了
I thought we'd seen the last of you when Odin died.
你是索尔
You are Thor…
雷霆之神
the God of Thunder.
雷霆不就是闪电的声音吗？
But is not thunder just the sound of lightning?
酸得好 爸
Good one, Dad.
宙斯 此事无关我们
Zeus, this is bigger than us.
他带走阿斯加德小孩
He's taken Asgardian children.
你以为我们是谁？神界警察？
Who do you think we are? The god police?
每个神都看顾着自己的子民
Every god watches over their own peoples.
不多不少 如此而已
Nothing more, nothing less.
阿斯加德人的问题
Asgardian problems…
是阿斯加德人的问题
are Asgardian problems.
强者竟堕落至此
How the mighty have fallen.
我的英雄宙斯
My hero, Zeus…
吓到皮皮剉
afraid.
我有几点要说
Couple of thing.
第一 没错 我会怕
One, yes, I am scared.
格尔有死灵剑
Gorr has the Necrosword…
有办法杀了我们
which means he could kill us.
那可不妙 第二
Not good. Two…
我知道你想做对的事
I know you're trying to do the right thing.
我了解
I understand.
但你只会引起恐慌
But all you do is cause a panic.
恐慌不好
Panic is not good.
我们在这里很安全
We are safe here.
你 朋友 你在这里很安全
You, my friend. You are safe here.
所以安啦 帅哥
So, chill, baby cake.
喝点酒 吃点葡萄
Have some wine, have some grape.
在全知之城
Anything goes here…
无拘无束
in Omnipotence City.
第三 别跟宙斯顶嘴
Three, don't talk back to Zeus.
我弹太大力了 帮你把衣服穿上
I flicked too hard. I put your clothes back on.
现在我把你衣服穿回去
Now I put your clothes back on!
弹 弹
Flick, flick.
因为这是众神的黄金神殿
For this is the Golden Temple of the god.
不是脱光光嘉年华
It's not a rudie-nudie festival.
如果不帮忙 至少让我们用你的武器
If you're not gonna help us, then at least let us use your weapon.
我们需要你的闪电
We need your lightning bolt.
我的闪电叫雷霆闪电
My lightning bolt is called Thunderbolt.
我想要用别人的秘密武器
So, I think to use somebody's secret weapon like this…
至少该把名字说对
that you should at least get the name right when you ask.
我能借用雷霆闪电吗？
Can I borrow Thunderbolt?
雷霆闪电
Thunderbolt!
不借
No!
别担心
Do not worry.
屠神者
The God Butcher…
他到不了永恒
he will not reach Eternity.
永恒？
Eternity?
到不了永恒是什么意思？
What does he mean, reach Eternity?
惨了
Oh, shit.
永恒是宇宙中心的强大存在
Eternity is a very powerful being at the center of the universe.
它会让率先到达的人实现愿望
It will grant the desire of the first person who reaches it.
就像许愿池？
So, it's like a wishing well?
你想叫屠神者的人有什么愿望？
What do you think a guy called the God Butcher would wish for?
如果他想找永恒祭坛 代表他能一举歼灭我们
If he seeks the Altar of Eternity, that means he could wipe us out at once.
宙斯 我们必须立刻采取行动
Zeus, we must act now.
他到不了的
He's not going to make it.
他没有钥匙
He doesn't have the key.
这是众神的使命吗？
Is this the purpose of the gods?
像懦夫一样躲在黄金宫殿里？
To hide away in a golden palace like cowards?
或许我们失去了方向
Maybe we have lost our way.
好 我们自己去阻止他
You know what? We'll stop him ourselves.
我恐怕不能同意
I am afraid I cannot allow that.
这是个秘密之地
This is a secret place…
只有众神知道
known only to the gods.
你知道我们在哪里
You know where we are.
屠神者可能利用你找到我们
The God Butcher could use you to find us.
那可不妙
This is no good.
所以…
So now…
你必须留下
you must stay.
卫兵
Guards!
嘿
Hey.
能执行我的计划了吗？
Can we do my plan now?
可以 痛扁他
Yes. Rush his bum.
赞啦
Hell, yeah!
你没说「上」
You didn't say, "Go."
我来了
Coming, guys!
索尔 接住
Thor, catch!
寇格
Korg!
瓦尔 蹲低
Val, duck!
寇格
Korg!
索尔
Thor.
不…寇格
Oh, no. No. Korg!
索尔 我快挂了
Thor, I'm perishing!
宙斯
Zeus!
你是下一个 奥汀森
You're next, Odinson!
那是闪电的声音
That's the sound of lightning.
不！
No!
寇格…
Korgi. Korgi!
索尔
Thor.
- 寇格？　- 我在下面
- Korgi? - I'm down here.
你在哪里？我救你出来 没事
Where? Where are you? I'm gonna get you out. It's okay.
- 寇格　- 在这里
- Korg. Korgi! - Here I am!
我没死
I didn't die!
天啊 对 你活着
Oh, my God. Yes! You're alive!
结果克罗南人只有嘴巴是活的
Turns out the only part of a Kronan that's alive is his mouth.
寇格 你快召唤羊儿
Korgi, listen. I need you to call the goats.
我尽量
I'll do my best.
用你的生命守护他
Guard him with your life.
我会的
I will.
准备去兜风了吗？
Ready to go for a ride?
你帮我注意背后
Now you've got my six.
8点钟方向 瓦尔
Eight o'clock, Val.
7点48分
7:48.
我可以的
I can do this, damn it.
不对…
No, that's not it. No, that's not it.
不
Nope.
寇格 嘴噘起来
Come on, Korg, purse those lips.
我成功了
I did it!
羊船过来救我们
And then the goat boat came in, rescued us…
我们破窗而出 结束
and we flew out the window. The end.
又是一场经典的索尔冒险
Another classic Thor adventure.
你竟然杀了宙斯
I can't believe you killed Zeus.
俗话说 千万别跟你的英雄见面
Well, you know what they say, never meet your heroes.
重点是我们就要去救你们了
But what's important is we are on our way to you right now.
你们还好吗？
How are you guys doing? Are you okay?
我们没事 有点害怕
We're all right. A little scared.
我知道害怕的感觉
Well, listen, I know what it's like to be scared.
告诉你们 我在你们这年纪
And I'll tell you, when I was your age…
应该不像你们这么勇敢
I don't think I would have been as brave as you.
真的吗？
Really?
你们是我见过最勇敢的阿斯加德人
In fact, might just be the bravest Asgardians that I've ever met.
你们都是
All of you.
我要你们继续勇敢下去 好吗？
So I need you to keep being brave, all right?
互相照顾 你们是一个团队
And take care of each other. You're a team now.
笼中小鬼队
Team Kids in a Cage.
你们做得到吗？
Can you do that?
可以 我们做得到
Yeah. I think we can do that.
我知道你们可以
I know you can.
对吧？
Right?
- 索尔？　- 是
- Thor? - Yeah.
我很高兴见到我的英雄
I'm glad I met my hero.
谢了 小老弟
Oh, thanks, buddy.
孩子们还好吗？
How are the children?
有点害怕 毕竟是孩子
As you can imagine, they're a little bit scared because they're kids…
但我说一切都会照计划进行
but I told them that everything is going to plan.
你骗他们？
Oh, so you lied to them?
我们还有计划吗？
We still have a plan?
- 有计划　- 没有
- Yes, there's a plan. - There's no plan.
- 有计划　- 没有计划
- There is a plan. - No. There's no plan.
我们无法召集一支军队
We failed to raise a god army…
寇格死了
Korg is dead.
- 他没死　- 我没死
- He's not dead. - I'm not dead.
他是一颗头 而你…
Well, he's a head. And you…
你丢脸丢到家
you got properly humiliated.
我只是脱光光 无所谓啦
No, I got properly naked, which I am okay with.
- 珍？　- 我无所谓
- Jane? - I was okay with it.
- 寇格　- 我喜欢
- Korg? - I loved it.
重点是我们要进入暗影领域
The point is, we are going into the Shadow Realm…
实力却比以前弱
weaker than we were before.
我们必死无疑
I mean, we're gonna die.
- 没人会死　- 是吗？
- No one's gonna die, okay? - Really?
安啦 我们在那里表现超杀的
Everything is fine. We did great back there.
- 我们杀了宙斯　- 你杀了宙斯
- We killed Zeus! - You killed Zeus.
那对全宇宙不见得是场灾难
I mean, that may or may not be catastrophic for the whole universe…
当然 整个神王国大概会…
and, sure, the entire god kingdom is probably going…
一辈子追杀我们
to hunt us down for the rest of our days…
但你抢走这件漂亮的武器
but listen, you stole this beautiful weapon.
它等于一支军队
All right? This is the army right here.
光滑细长 威力强大 美丽耀眼
It's sleek, it's slender, it's powerful, it's beautiful…
给你 我想给你用 瓦尔基丽
For you. I love it for you, Valkyrie.
我不是很爱啦
I mean, it's not really what I'm into…
我有自己的武器
'cause I've got my weapon out there.
借用一下
Can I borrow that for a second?
你在这里 老朋友
There you are, old friend.
当时进场的气势不得了
That was quite an entrance back there.
听我说
Listen…
我们没事吧？
are we good?
嗯？
Yeah?
我知道前武器待在身边是有点怪
I mean, I know it's a little weird having my ex-weapon around…
可是雷神之锤是过去式了
but come on, Mjolnir, in the past.
现在只有你和我
It's you and me now, buddy.
你知道吗？
You know what?
你该喝第一杯啤酒了 怎么样？
I think it's time for your first beer. What do you say?
好喝
Delicious.
抱歉我们最近吵架了
I'm sorry we've been fighting lately.
嘿
Hey.
Oh, hey.
景色很棒吧？
It's quite the view, huh?
对 很美
Yeah. Beautiful.
我想说你在那里的表现很了不起
I just want to say that was very, very impressive what you did back there.
你和雷神之锤
You and Mjolnir, you know.
是啊
Yeah.
- 太空海豚　- 什么？
- Space dolphins. - What?
你该看看太空海豚
You should see some space dolphins…
什么？
What?
- 哇　- 对啊
- Wow. - Yeah.
好美啊
Beautiful.
好美 好罕见
So beautiful. So rare.
非常忠心的动物
Very loyal creatures.
它们会在一起一辈子 六只一组
They mate for life, in packs of six.
只为了爱
Just love.
黑的尼尼诺尼 白的分尼风尼
With a hey ninny-nonny and a fair finny-fonny.
兄弟 你看起来好辣
Ooh, brother man, you look so hot.
我想伸进你的岩石缝
I wanna get in your rocks.
当我们凑在一起 天雷勾动地火
When we get together We're gonna get it on.
我们就会制造一些宝宝
And we're all gonna make some babies.
这是我爸在追
That is the song that my dad.
我另一个爸爸时唱的歌
sang to my other dad when they were courting.
两个克罗南人
When two Kronans wanna make a baby,
想生孩子就到山上
they get together inside a mountain…
找一座小熔岩池
and they go down to a little lava pool,
在熔岩上方牵手
and they hold hands over the hot lava…
经过一个月 他们的手分开
and then, after a month, they pull their hands apart…
就会创造一个漂亮的克罗南小男孩
and they find they've created a beautiful new Kronan baby boy.
真有意思 好火辣
Fascinating. And hot.
你有过心上人吗？
Did you ever have a special someone?
我有过好多心上人
I've had so many special someones.
可是 不晓得
But I don't know…
我不知道还要不要
I don't know if I want that again.
因为你在战争中失去女友
Is that because you lost your girlfriend in battle.
无法原谅自己？
and never forgave yourself?
现在你想靠喝酒或打炮找答案
And now, you're just trying to find answers in the bottom of a bottle…
却只能麻痹痛苦的感觉
or some meaningless dalliance, which only serves to numb the pain…
无法带来真正的幸福或满足？
instead of bringing you real happiness or satisfaction?
对 差不多是那样
Yeah. Something like that.
好美 好美
Beautiful. Beautiful things.
珍
Jane.
索尔
Thor.
我想对你感到糟糕
I wanna feel shitty about you.
什么？
What?
我想有糟糕的感觉 对象是你
I wanna feel shitty about something and I think that's you.
有听没有懂
Not really getting any better.
是吗？可恶
It's not, is it? Damn it.
我朋友说失去爱之后感觉糟糕
My friend, he told me that it's better to feel shitty…
比从来没经历爱情
from losing love than it is to never experience love…
没感觉 感到空虚来得好
and to feel nothing at all, to feel empty…
我想他说得对
and I think he was right…
那正是我长久以来的感受
which is how I've been feeling for a long time.
我把别人推开 跟他们保持距离
I've pushed people away, kept them at a distance…
因为害怕失去
because of the fear of that loss…
但我不想那样了 不要那种生活
but I don't wanna do that anymore. I don't wanna live like that.
封闭心房比感到痛苦好
Better to close off your heart than feel the pain.
我就是那样 我封闭了心房
That's what I did, yes. I closed off my heart…
开始冥想 你有冥想吗？
and I meditated. Did you meditate?
没有 那好无聊
No. It's so boring.
它让我更愤怒
It actually made me more angry.
我不想再把自己交给命运
But I'm tired of giving myself over to the idea of fate…
不想搞懂宇宙要我怎么样
and trying to figure out what the universe wants from me.
我想活在当下 彷佛没有明天
I wanna live in the moment, I wanna live like there's no tomorrow…
不再诚惶诚恐过日子
throw caution to the wind.
我想跟你在一起 珍
I wanna be with you, Jane.
你觉得呢？
What do you say?
我得了癌症
I have cancer.
你说什么？
I'm sorry. What?
我生病了
I'm sick.
- 发生什么事？　- 掰
- Wait. What's happening? - Bye.
不…珍…等一下
No, no, no. Jane, Jane, Jane. Wait, wait, wait. Jane.
我说了什么？我开玩笑的
What did I say? I didn't mean that. Just kidding.
我才没得癌症
I don't have cancer.
我们去惩奸除恶吧
Let's go smash something.
珍 我很遗憾
Jane, I'm so sorry.
别替我遗憾
Don't be sorry for me.
何时发现的？
When did you find out?
六个月前
Like six months ago.
我只是疲倦 他们就说我第四期
I was just feeling tired, and then they told me I have Stage Four.
叫我安排后事
Get my affairs in order.
接着我听到雷神之锤呼唤我
And then I heard Mjolnir calling me…
我想如果科学没有用
so I thought maybe, if science isn't working…
或许维京人的太空魔力可以
maybe Viking space magic.
所以你来到新阿斯加德
That's why you came to New Asgard.
对 我想锤子或许能治愈我
Yeah, I thought the hammer maybe could cure me…
我想病情好转了
and I think it's getting better.
或许没有
Maybe not.
珍 我们都不知道能活多久
Jane, none of us know how long we have.
不知道明天会如何
We don't know what tomorrow holds.
雷神之锤
And Mjolnir…
雷神之锤选择了你
Mjolnir chose you.
因为你值得
And it chose you because you're worthy.
这很了不起
And that's something.
刚认识你时
When I first met you…
我不值得 无法举起那把锤子
I was unworthy. I was unable to pick up that hammer.
你教我
But you taught me…
最崇高的使命莫过于帮助受难的人
there is no greater purpose than to help those in need.
你让我有了价值
You made me worthy.
不管你想怎么做 我们都能一起行动
So whatever you wanna do, we can do together.
好
Okay.
你想怎么做？
Now what do you wanna do?
我想带那些孩子回到家人身边
I wanna get those children back to their families.
我想完成那项任务
I wanna finish that mission.
果然是雷神
Spoken like a true Thor.
现在有什么感觉？
How do you feel now?
好害怕
So scared.
你的感觉呢？
How are you feeling?
糟糕
Shitty.
多糟糕？
How shitty?
- 真的超糟糕　- 那…
- Really shitty. - Well, then…
不知道他们俩在聊什么
I wonder what those two are talking about out there.
他们不是在聊天
Yeah, they're not talking.
你想他们会不会在热熔岩池上牵手
Do you think those two will ever hold hands over a hot lava pool.
制造雷神宝宝
and make a Thor baby?
可惜不太可能
It's unlikely, sadly.
太可惜了 索尔会是个好爸爸
That's too bad. I think Thor would make a great dad.
喂 我们到了
Hey. We're here.
色彩都到哪去了？
Where did all the color go?
他们不在这里
They're not here.
他们在哪？
Where are they?
这是什么地方？
What the hell is this place?
彩虹桥是钥匙？
Bifrost is the key?
这是陷阱
It's a trap!
你干嘛把风暴破坏者丢出窗外？
You wanna tell me why you just threw Stormbreaker out the window?
他得用它来打开永恒之门
He needs it to open the Gates of Eternity.
我们不能老是这样见面
We really have to stop meeting like this.
召唤斧头
Call the axe.
你召唤牙医我就召唤斧头
I'll call the axe when you call the dentist.
召唤斧头
Call the axe.
告诉我孩子在哪 不然我杀了你
Tell me where the children are or I'm gonna kill you.
召唤斧头
Call the axe.
你这样也算神啊
Some god you are.
你根本不懂怎么当神
You know nothing of being a god.
你向众神求助 祂们袖手旁观
You went to the gods for help, and they did nothing.
我们在那方面半斤八两
We're alike in that sense.
他跟你完全不同
He's nothing like you.
你说什么？
What was that?
我说他跟你完全不同
I said he's nothing like you.
没错
That's right.
我不是伪君子 我其实是在创造和平
I'm not a hypocrite. I'm truly creating peace.
和平？你残杀无辜的神
Peace? You're murdering innocent gods.
无辜？
Innocent?
你是瓦尔基丽吗？
Are you a Valkyrie?
对
Yes.
真让人兴奋
How exciting!
众神也让你失望了
Oh, the gods failed you, too…
当你们姊妹淘无意中引起大屠杀
when your sisterhood was led to slaughter.
你不准说…
Don't you dare speak…
你有向神祈祷吗…
Did you pray to the gods…
当你爱的女人在战场上奄奄一息？
when the women you loved laid dying on the battlefield?
当你的家人惨遭杀害
Did you beg them for help…
你有乞求祂们帮忙吗？
as your family was massacred?
聊得真开心
Good chat.
这一个
This one.
你很有意思
You're interesting.
你不一样
You're different.
对
Yes.
你快死了
You're dying.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我们同病相怜
We're on the same path.
如同死灵剑赋予我力量
Just as the sword empowered me…
那锤子也给了你力量
the hammer empowered you.
但它没有改变你的命运
But it did nothing to change your fate.
众神会利用你
The gods will use you…
却不会救你
but they will not help you.
我们得不到永恒的恩典
There is no eternal reward for us.
她就快走了
She'll be gone soon.
知道谁不会救她吗？
And you know who won't help her?
我让你猜一次
I'll give you one guess.
我知道你的痛苦
I know your pain.
爱就是痛苦
Love is pain.
我曾经有个女儿
I had a daughter once.
我相信一个更高的神灵
I put my faith in a higher power…
希望祂会救她
hoping it would save her…
而她…
and she…
却死了
died.
现在我懂了
Now I understand.
我女儿算好运
My daughter is the lucky one.
她不必在一个充满苦难的世界…
She does not have to grow up in a world of suffering…
长大
and pain…
邪恶众神掌控的世界
run by wicked gods.
选择爱
Choose love.
召唤斧头
Call the axe.
召唤…
Call…
斧头
the axe.
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我要杀了那家伙
I wanna kill this guy.
我也是 但得活捉
So do I, but we have to take him alive.
他是找到那些孩子的唯一线索
He's our only link to finding those children.
谢谢你 羊先生
Thank you, Mr. Goat.
瓦尔
Val!
我们得带她离开
We gotta get her out of here!
我带你走
Hey. I got you.
我们来了 快走吧
Hey, guys, we're here. Come on, let's go.
风暴破坏者 带我们回家
Stormbreaker, take us home.
扩散速度前所未见
…at a rate that none of us have seen before.
我们能尝试更积极的疗法
Look, there are other more aggressive forms of treatment we can try…
但她身体的抗癌能力受到影响
but something's affecting her body's ability to fight the cancer.
很遗憾 索尔
I'm sorry, Thor.
你在这里
There you are. Okay.
外面怎么了？
What's goin' on out there?
有白痴做了一台没门的冰箱 超扯
Some moron made a fridge without a door. Can you believe it?
放心 我把它打开 拿了各种好料
Not to worry. Got it open and got you all sorts of goodies.
瓦尔还好吗？
How's Val?
她很痛苦 但情况稳定
She's in a lot of pain, but she is stable.
那就好
Okay, good.
你把这个拿掉…
Now you just gotta get this out of my…
不行 插着别动
No, no, no. That's gotta stay in there.
神药正在发挥作用
That's all the magic potions and elixirs doing their thing, so…
我出去一下 救回孩子 干掉那坏蛋
I'm just gonna pop out for a moment, pick up the kids, kill the bad guy…
马上就回来
and then I'll come straight back.
你不找我去？
You're going without me?
对
Yeah.
不是说什么都要一起做吗？
What happened to, like, doing everything together?
他会利用孩子分散你注意力
He's gonna use those kids to distract you.
你需要我
You need me.
我是需要你 需要你活下去
I do need you, Jane. I need you alive.
在战场上并肩对抗格尔固然很好
It'd be great to have you on the battlefield, fighting Gorr side by side…
但那锤子会害死你
but that hammer is killing you.
每次使用 你就耗尽力气
Every time you use it, it's draining all of your mortal strength…
导致你的身体无力抗癌
leaving your body unable to fight the cancer.
不是要活得彷佛没有明天吗？
What happened to, "Live like there's no tomorrow"?
当时我不知道你可能没有明天
Well, that's before I knew you might not have one.
那何不再进行一次冒险？
Why not have one more adventure?
珍 有活命的机会就得把握
Jane, if there's a chance to live, you have to take it.
没罹癌的雷神只会出一张嘴
Spoken like a true Thor who does not have cancer.
我是新墨西哥来的冷静天体物理学家
I know I seem like some cool astrophysicist from New Mexico…
美梦都成真了 但看看我
just living the dream, but look at me.
我要继续奋战 我是女雷神
I wanna keep fighting. I'm the Mighty Thor.
你却要阻止我？
And you want me not to do that?
继续治疗有什么意义？
What's the point of more time of this?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
我一直爱着你
I've always loved you.
这是我们在一起的机会
And this is a chance for us.
如果你再举起那把锤子 机会就没了
But if you pick up that damn hammer again, then that chance is gone.
你自己决定 珍
It's your choice, Jane.
但我会后悔一辈子 如果没求你留下
But I'd regret it every single day if I didn't ask you to stay here…
好让我们一起设法解决
so we could try and figure this out together.
你最好回来找我
You better come back to me.
我会尽快赶回来
I'm coming back as soon as I can.
- 祝你好运　- 我会打断他的腿
- Break a leg. - I'll break all his legs.
别忘了永恒之门位于
Remember that the Gate to Eternity is at the literal center…
- 宇宙中心 - 宇宙嘛 对
- of the universe. - Universe. Yes.
如果经过彗星群…
If you go past the cluster of comets…
对 我们谈过 我不会迷路
Yes, yes, I know. We've been over this. I'm not gonna get lost.
你的伤口感觉怎么样？
So how you feeling with the old stab wound?
我的肾脏好像没了
I think I lost my kidney.
完全没了？
Gone completely?
我很想陪你去
I wish I could join you…
但我大概会死 那样没帮助
but I'd probably die, and that won't help get the kids back…
你得自己去
so you'll have to go alone.
你只要摧毁那把剑
All you have to do is destroy that sword.
那是他力量的来源 没了他就撑不久
It's his source of power. He won't survive long without it.
嘿 不要死
Hey. Don't die.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
永恒
Eternity.
终于
Finally.
快啊…
Come on.
小朋友
Hey, kids.
我就知道他会来
I knew he'd come.
快跑
Go!
快跑 小朋友
Go, kids!
大家没事吧？靠过来
Everyone okay? All right, gather round. Gather round.
好高兴见到你本人 好开心
Good to see you in person, buddy. Good to see you.
听好 以下是我们的计划
All right, listen up. Here's the plan.
我们偷偷溜到风暴破坏者那边
We're gonna sneak our way towards Stormbreaker…
小心别碰上那些黑影大怪兽
being very careful not to bump into any of those big shadow monsters.
它们就在我背后吧？
They're behind me, aren't they?
有谁打过仗吗？
Does anyone here have battle experience?
打过仗？
Battle experience?
择期不如撞日
Well, no time to learn like the present.
我们不像你这么壮 我们是小孩子
We're not strong like you. We're just kids.
别忘了你们是阿斯加德小孩
Hey, don't forget you're Asgardian kids.
我不是 我是狼人小孩
I'm not. I'm just a Lycan kid.
我是迈达斯人小孩
And I'm a Midassian kid.
- 我是法利加人　- 好
- I'm Falligarian. - Okay, okay.
但今天你们是阿斯加德人
But today you're Asgardians.
现在拿起武器
Now collect your weapons.
什么？
What?
去找任何能用的东西
Go and find anything you can pick up.
拿来这里
Bring it back here.
快点
Hurry, hurry!
好 快点
Okay, cool. Come on!
它们越来越靠近 快点
They're getting closer. Hurry up!
快啊
Come on!
今天我们将名留青史
Today is a day that will go down in history.
今天将是后代不会遗忘的一天
Today is the day they will talk about for generations to come.
今天我们是太空维京人
Today we are Space Vikings!
举起武器 敬礼
Present arms!
任何人拿起这些武器 有信心能返家
Whosoever holds these weapons, and believes in getting home…
只要秉持忠心 就值得
if they be true of heart is therefore worthy…
将拥有…
and shall possess…
但有时限…
for limited time only…
雷神索尔的力量
the power of Thor!
艾克索将军
General Axl…
带领你的军队到斧头那边
lead your army to that axe.
我们会全力以赴
We shall do our worst.
为了阿斯加德
For Asgard.
赞啦！
Yeah!
不会吧
No.
珍
Jane.
摧毁那把剑 他就会死
We destroy that sword and he's dead.
入口快开了 你得阻止风暴破坏者
The gateway's almost open. You gotta stop Stormbreaker.
没关系 我对付他
It's okay. I got him.
风暴破坏者 快停止
Stormbreaker, stop this!
清醒一点 瞧你干的好事
Get a hold of yourself. Look what you're doing!
我把你拔起来
I'm gonna get you out of there.
起来…
Come on. Come on, buddy.
放开我的朋友
Let go of my friend.
你输了 索尔女士
You've lost, Lady Thor.
首先
First off…
我叫女雷神
the name is Mighty Thor.
第二
And secondly…
如果你不会说女雷神
if you can't say Mighty Thor…
我能接受珍佛斯特博士
I'll accept Doctor Jane Foster.
第三
And thirdly…
吃我的锤子
Eat my hammer!
风暴破坏者
Stormbreaker!
我就知道你有办法
I knew you could do it.
艾克索 带他们回家
Axl! Get them home!
珍？
Jane?
我没事
I'm okay.
你必须阻止他
You have to stop him.
格尔 停止
Gorr! Stop!
如果停止 我算…
What kind of father would I be…
哪门子父亲？
if I stopped?
我了解你的痛苦 但这不是办法
I know your pain, but this isn't the way.
你寻求的不是死亡或复仇
It's not death or revenge that you seek.
我寻求的是什么？
What do I seek?
你寻求的是爱
You seek love.
爱？
Love?
我为何要寻求爱？
Why should I seek love?
那是任何人都想要的
Because it's all any of us want.
你…
How…
竟敢转身而去？
dare you turn your back on me?
你赢了 格尔
You've won, Gorr.
我生命最后的时刻能陪她
Why would I spend my last moments with you…
何必与你共度？
when I can be with her?
我选择爱
I choose love.
你也能 你能救她回来
You can, too. You can bring her back.
许你的愿吧
Make your wish.
我快死了
I'm dying.
没人能照顾她
She would have no one.
她会孤单无依
She would be alone.
她不会孤单
She won't be alone.
我的爱
My love.
我好想你
I've missed you so much.
我也想你
I missed you too.
我好抱歉
I'm so sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
自从我举起那把锤子
Ever since I picked up that hammer…
好像…
it's like…
我多了一条命
I've gotten an extra life.
那实在…
And it was…
很神奇
magical.
对一个人类来说还不赖
Not too bad for a human.
对一个神也不错
Not too bad for a god.
我想到我的口号了
Hey. I think I figured out my catchphrase.
- 是什么？　- 过来
- Oh, yeah? What is it? - Come close…
好极了
It's perfect.
目前最棒的一个
It's the best one yet.
谢谢
Thanks.
继续敞开你的心房
Keep your heart open.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
保护她
Protect her.
保护我的爱
Protect my love.
让我告诉你们一个太空维京人的传奇
Let me tell you the legend of the Space Viking…
就是女雷神 又名珍佛斯特
AKA the Mighty Thor, AKA Dr. Jane Foster.
她的牺牲拯救了宇宙
Her sacrifice saved the universe…
让我们了解什么叫活得有价值
and taught us all what it means to be worthy.
她救了众神的孩子
She helped the children of the gods…
他们搭乘雷射光回家
who laser-beamed their way back home…
回到从渔村变观光景点的家
to their dozy little fishing village turned tourist destination.
艾克索
Axl!
我好想你
I missed you.
- 你还好吗？　- 我没事
- Are you okay? - I'm fine. I'm okay.
- 你确定吗？　- 没事
- Are you sure? - I'm okay.
小朋友又变成天真的孩子
The kids were safe to be kids again.
大声点 三
Louder, three!
脚站开一点
Widen your stance.
尤其在国王逼他们上防身课之后
Especially after their king made them all go to self-defense classes.
看看那些初出茅庐的太空维京人
Look at all those budding Space Vikings.
最重要的部分
And the most important part.
喊杀！
The war cry!
就连海姆达尔的儿子
Even Heimdall's son…
艾克索海姆达尔
Axl Heimdallson…
现在具有跟父亲一样的魔眼
who could now do his dad's freaky eye magic…
也成了一个小战士
was becoming quite the warrior.
阿斯加德的未来有希望了
The future of Asgard was secure.
说到未来 我正在开创自己的未来
Speaking of futures, I was forging one of my own…
毕竟现在身体长回来了
now that my body's grown back…
和一个叫杜恩的男生一起
with a dude I met called Dwayne.
你问 那索尔呢？
And what about Thor, you ask?
索尔展开全新的旅程
He embarked on a new journey…
因为他发现生活目标 一个他爱的人
because he had found something to live for, something to love for.
这个人让他从悲伤之神变成老爸之神
A little someone who turned him from Sad God into Dad God.
早餐上桌啰 慢用
Breakfast is served.
哈啰 好了
Hello. There you go.
吃早餐
Hey. Breakfast.
请问一下 那是什么？
Excuse me. What is that?
燕麦煎饼 来自地球
They're pan-flaps. From Earth.
我不喜欢燕麦煎饼
I don't think I like pan-flaps.
- 你很爱吃　- 不爱
- You love them. - No, I don't.
- 你爱　- 我从来没吃过
- Yes, you do. - I've never had that in my life.
快吃 我们该走了 快迟到了
Come on. Eat up. We have to go. We're gonna be late.
你的靴子呢？
Now where are your boots?
我穿好了
I'm wearing them.
不能穿那双
You're not wearing those.
- 我要　- 不行
- Yes, I am. - No, you're not.
就是要
Yes, I am.
不行
No. You're not.
去死吧 恶魔
Go to hell, demon!
哇
Wow!
全新的 毁了 谢谢你喔
Brand new, now destroyed. Thank you very much.
好吧 随便你
You know what? You wear what you want.
脚痛就别对我唉唉叫
Don't come complaining to me when your feet get sore, all right?
我不会同情你
You'll get no sympathy here from me.
好啦 我穿靴子
Fine, I'll wear the boots.
谢谢
Thank you.
记住我妈常说的
Remember what my mother used to tell me.
听大人的话
Listen to the grown-ups…
看到有人害怕或被欺负
and if you see anyone scared or being picked on…
- 就照顾他们 好吗？　- 好
- you look after them, okay? - Okay.
最重要的是 玩得开心
And most of all, have fun.
- 懂了　- 懂了
- Gotcha. - Gotcha.
雷神之锤呢？我放在哪？
Now where is Mjolnir? Where did I put him?
那边 在床上睡觉
Over there. Sleeping in the bed.
在床上
In the bed.
哇
Oh, wow.
这洗不掉了
That is not coming off.
你做了什么好事？
What did you do?
她以前看起来好无聊
She looked boring before.
我想也是
Yeah. Suppose it did.
我喜欢
I love it.
很有创意
Very creative.
好
Okay.
看到那边的外星人了吗？
Now, you see the aliens down there?
- 有条纹的　- 他们看起来是好人
- The stripy ones? - They look nice.
没错 所以我们得照顾他们
Yeah, they are nice. That's why we have to look after them.
懂了 保护好人
Got it. Protect the nice ones.
我爱你 小甜心
I love you, sweetie.
我爱你 索尔叔叔
Love you, Uncle Thor.
他们永远都会保护我们
They will always be there for us.
太空维京人和诞生自永恒
The Space Viking and his girl, born from Eternity.
拥有神力的女孩
With the powers of a god.
两名战士
Two warriors…
为无力反抗的人打赢正义之战
fighting the good fight for those who can't fight good.
他们周游宇宙 被取了许多名字
They have traveled far, and have been given many names.
但对那些最了解他们的人来说
But to those who know them best…
他们就叫…
they are simply known…
爱与雷霆
as Love and Thunder.
《雷神4：爱与雷霆》
以往身为一个神 是有意义的
It used to be that being a god, it meant something.
人们会轻唤你的名字
People would whisper your name…
分享他们最真诚的希望与梦想
before sharing their deepest hopes and dreams.
他们求你大发慈悲
They begged you for mercy…
连你有没有在听都不知道
without ever knowing if you were actually listening.
现在…
Now…
他们望着天空
you know, they look to the sky…
不向我们求闪电
they don't ask us for lightning.
不向我们求雨
They don't ask us for rain.
只想到看所谓的超级英雄
They just want to see one of their so-called superheroes.
我们何时成了笑话？
When did we become the joke?
不
No.
不能这样下去
No more.
他们将再度畏惧我们
They will fear us again…
只要索尔奥汀森死
when Thor Odinson falls from the sky.
你听懂了吗 海克力士？
Do you understand me, Hercules?
你听懂了吗 儿子？
Do you understand me, my son?
懂 父亲
Yes, Father.
什么？
What?
嘿
Hey.
珍佛斯特
Jane Foster.
海姆达尔
Heimdall.
你死了
I see you're dead now.
是啊
Yeah.
谢谢你照顾我儿子
Thank you for looking after my son.
非常欢迎你来到众神之地
You are very welcome here, to the land of the gods.
欢迎莅临英灵殿
Welcome to Valhalla.
雷神索尔将再度回归